# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I'm going to share a homestyle dish with you.
# 葱香牛肉
Stir-fried Beef with Scallion
# 首先我们准备外脊牛肉350克
First let's prepare 350 grams of top sirloin.
# 先切成8毫米左右的厚片备用
Cut into 8 mm thick slices.
# 然后用刀背将牛肉敲散备用
Then use the back of a knife to break up the beef.
# 同学们敲的时候最好横竖兼顾
Strike both horizontally and vertically on the beef.
# 这一步的目的是让牛肉更加松散入味
The purpose of this step is to make the beef's texture more loose and flavourful.
# 敲散之后切成小条备用
And then cut into small strips
# 然后放入盆中加入适量的清水清洗几遍
Then put the beef in a bowl with some water and wash it several times
# 通常来说新鲜的牛肉中含有大量的血水
Usually fresh beef has a lot of blood in it.
# 而牛肉最大的腥味就在血水中
And the biggest gamey taste in beef is in the blood.
# 去除血水最好的办法就是浸泡或者清洗
The best way to get rid of blood is by soaking or washing
# 下一步开始腌制
Next, start marinating.
# 首先我们在盆中加入适量的玉米淀粉（约2克）
First we add some cornstarch to a big bowl (about 2 grams)
# 再加入适量的蚝油（约3克）
Add some oyster sauce (about 3 grams)
# 加入生抽酱油3克
Add 3g of light soy sauce
# 加入食用盐0.5克
Add 0.5g of table salt
# 加入适量的老抽调底色（约3克）
Add some dark soy sauce for the color (about 3 grams)
# 加入土豆淀粉15克
Add 15g of potato starch
# 加入等量的清水（15克）
Add the same amount of water (15 g)
# 搅拌均匀之后再下入牛肉
Stir and mix well before adding the beef.
# 然后顺着一个方向搅拌牛肉将所有的调料水吸收干净
Then add in the beef and stir in one direction to absorb all the seasoning.
# 最后加入适量的植物油将牛肉“封口”
Finally, add some vegetable oil to "seal" the beef.
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Start preparing the other ingredients next.
# 准备大葱120克切成小小的短节备用
Prepare 120 grams of scallion, cut into small short segments.
# 同学们最好选择大葱这样才经得起“煎”
Choose the big scallion or big spring onions that can stand the frying.
# 准备大红椒1个去籽之后切成小段备用
Prepare 1 red bell pepper, remove the seeds and cut into small segments.
# 准备生姜25克切成小段备用
Prepare 25 grams of ginger cut into small segments.
# 准备几颗大蒜切成蒜片备用
Prepare a few garlic cut into thin slices
# 下一步开始制作
Start cooking next.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First let's heat up the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的底油
Once the wok is hot, add some base oil.
# 油温5成热之后将切好的大葱下锅煎成金黄色
When the oil temperature about 50%(150 ℃) hot, fry the chopped scallions until they are golden.
# 同学们这个过程最好开中火煎制
This process is best done on medium heat.
# 小火容易将大葱煎软发干
If fry the scallions on low heat, they will become soft and dry.
# 大葱煎成金黄色之后捞出备用
Fry the scallions until golden and remove from the wok.
# 然后再将腌制好的牛肉均匀地下入锅中
Then add the marinated beef evenly to the wok
# 牛肉下锅之后转中小火将牛肉煎制3分钟左右
Once the beef is in the pan, turn the heat to medium-low and sear the beef for about 3 minutes.
# 同学们在这个过程中尽量不要翻动
Try not to move the beef during the process.
# 煎至牛肉发黄之后再翻过来煎另外一面
When the beef become browned, then flip them over and brown the other side.
# 中途有一点点粘锅属于正常现象
It's normal for the wok to stick a little bit during this process.
# 3分钟之后加入切好的生姜段和蒜片
After 3 minutes add the ginger and garlic.
# 料头爆出香味之后开始调味
After the aroma comes out, start seasoning.
# 加入少许生抽酱油从锅边淋入
Add a bit light soy sauce from the side of the wok.
# 加入适量的蚝油调咸鲜味
Add some oyster sauce to adjust the taste.
# 加入少许的老抽调色
Add a touch of dark soy sauce for the color
# 小火翻炒均匀之后再加入切好的大红椒段
Stir-fry everything on low heat, then add the red pepper.
# 红椒段炒至断生之后再加入煎好的大葱段
Stir-fry the red peppers until they half cook, then add the fried scallions.
# 翻炒几下之后加入适量的水淀粉略微收汁即可出菜
Stir-fry for another few times, then add some slurry to dense the sauce and it's ready to serve.
# 一道非常美味的葱香牛肉就制作完成
A very tasty Stir-fried Beef with Scallion is ready.
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一 牛肉最好选择里脊或者外脊
First, the best choice of beef is loin or sirloin.
# 外脊肉通常比里脊肉略老一些
The sirloin is usually slightly tougher than the tenderloin.
# 且有较多较大的肌纤维
There are more larger muscle fibers.
# 所以需要切片之后用刀背敲打
So it needs to be sliced and then beaten with the back of a knife.
# 第二 大葱直接下锅炒和事先煎制是两种不同的香味
Second, there will be two different flavors, if you stir-fry the scallions during the cooking process or pre-fry them beforehand.
# 后者只有香味且没有葱辣味
If you pre-fry them, the aroma of scallion is great and it has no spicy flavor.
# 此方法借鉴了葱烧海参的原理
The same principle is applied to stir-fried sea cucumbers with scallions.
# 第三 凡是炒肉类都必须控制其咸度不能过咸
Third, when you cook with meat, you must control the saltiness of the meat.
# 正所谓咸鱼淡肉
There is such a thing as salty fish but light meat.
# 葱香牛肉的技术总结完毕
That's the technique summary for Stir-fried Beef with Scallion